就要三个美味的自制小蛋糕  对吧
So that's three of our delicious homemade cupcakes.
别给我  你们都摸过了
Nope, can't. You touched them.
抱歉  流感季节  我没医保
Sorry, flu season, no health care.
知道你的净手液被我换成润滑油了吧
You realized I replaced that purell with K.Y., right?
麦克斯  你是开玩笑的对吧
Max, please say you're kidding.
废话  我逗你玩呢
Of course, I'm kidding.
我买不起润滑油  唯有以眼泪润滑
I can't afford lube. I just use my tears.
麦克斯  你可千万别乱搞我的净手液
Max, seriously, don't mess with my hand sanitizer.
我今年已经被贫穷缠上了
I've already caught poverty this year
我可不想再染上流感
and I refuse to catch the flu.
我只能勤擦洗手液  避免任何肢体接触
I just have to keep cleaning my hands and not touch anyone.
卡洛琳  这是十号桌的账单
Caroline, I have check from table ten.
好  放这儿就行
Okay, just place it right there.
小费给得真多啊...
That's a big tip...
在印尼  你们这样就得结婚了
You know, in Indonesia, you'd be married now.
我感觉到我快生病了
I'm gonna get sick, I know it.
你没事的
You're fine.
没事个屁  他把病菌全"喷射"进我嘴里了
Fine? Han just unloaded into my mouth.
恭喜你们  终于"实干"上了
Congratulations, you both finally got some action.
我可生不起病  也请不起病假
I can't afford to get sick and miss work.
我需要钱买抗生素
I need to get some antibiotics.
你是个穷人
You are poor now.
穷人才不会没事就跑去买抗生素
Poor people don't just run out and buy antibiotics.
穷人就该硬起  死扛  跟病毒单挑
We man up, grow a pair, stare germs in the face.
比如这根
Like this French fry
被不停咳嗽男吃过的薯条
from that guy who couldn't stop coughing.
麦克斯  别啊  别
Max, no, no--oh!
姐牛吧
Booyah!
就算这样  我也没生过病或去过诊所
And I haven't ever been sick or to a clinic.
对了  计划生育诊所除外
And, no, planned parenthood doesn't count.
哎哟妈呀  她颤颤悠悠  摇摇晃晃
Well, well, well, she weebles and she wobbles,
但步履坚定  胸前不倒
but she don't fall down.
厄尔  你嘴又甜又会调戏人家
Oh, Earl, you're so naughty and nice.
那我再用眼神调戏你一回吧
And I'll be checking you out twice.
苏菲  随便坐啊
Hey, Sophie, sit anywhere you like.
我看看
Oh, uh, let's see.
哪个位置的灯光能让我显得最明媚动人啊
Where is lighting that will make me look most attractive?
我说啥呢  我坐哪都是仪态万千
What am I saying? I look good everywhere.
我要跟我的网友首次见面
I am meeting man for first time that I met online.
不知道他到了没
I wonder if he's here yet.
除非他是个单身
Well unless you've been cruising singles
小费给得又抠门的男人  不然应该没到
who don't leave enough singles, I'd say no.
麦克斯  如果这场约会是大"凶"之...
You know, Max, if my date turned out to be big bust--
能比咱们"胸"吗
what, bigger than ours?
你记得过来说突然有急事
Then you come over and say that something suddenly came up
我得先走  知道吗
and that I have to go, okay?
天啊  肯定是他了
Oh, my gosh, this must be him.
你是苏菲·科臣斯基吧
You must be Sophie Kuchenski.
我是  瑟格特·比罗斯基
I'm Serguisz Bilowski.
我好喜欢你的连衣裙啊  真好看
Wow, I love your dress, I love that!
突然有事  你得走了
Something came up and you have to go.
不  不  这好得很
No, no this is perfect.
我们坐下吧
Would you like to sit down?
我得先去嘘嘘一下吧
Just let me run to the little boys rooms first.
-可以吗  -没问题
- Okay? - Okay.
他是谁啊
Who is that?
他是苏菲的新男朋友
That's Sophie's new boyfriend.
那这个男的男朋友又在哪
I see, and where's his boyfriend?
你好吗
Hello.
很高兴再次见到你
Nice to see you again.
我现在除了衣服  全身上下无一不硬
And right now, it's the only thing soft about me.
趁我的对象还在厕所  你快滚吧
Please go away before my date comes back from the men's room.
你还带男人来我地盘啦
You have brought other man in here?
是啊  我们在波兰人交友网站认识的
Yes, I met him on Polish dating site.
波兰交友管道网
On polemeetpole.com
何须上网找呢
You didn't have to go online.
我的"管子"随时欢迎你
You could meet my pole any time.
不可能  你别做梦了
No, this will never happen.
你不是我的型
You're not my type.
那你喜欢什么型
Well, what is your type?
里面有自动干手机帮你吹呢
Wow, they have those automatic hand dryers that blow you.
人家好喜欢被那样吹哦
I love being blown like that.
你胸前犹如两个巨大的橘色交通锥
Those look like two giant orange traffic cones.
是要警告我"此处不能停"吗
Are you trying to tell me not to park there?
她是个淑女
This is a lady.
请你放尊重点
Show her some respect.
苏菲居然找了个新男人
Sophie has new man in her life.
我气的两眼都要发直了
I am so mad I cannot see straight.
我看着也觉得他的一点都不"直"[同性恋]
Well, I'm looking right at him and I don't see straight either.
麦克斯  我好像有点发烧
Max, I think I'm running a slight fever.
感觉一下我额头
Feel my forehead.
你还不了解我吗
Look, you should have learned by now--
我感觉不到任何东西
I don't feel anything.
卡洛琳  我把医生的地址写下了
Caroline, I've written down address of drug store
他的诊所在南威廉斯堡的药局里
in South Williamsburg that has a doctor on site.
给  医药费我出
Here, I will pay for it.
可如果是癌症
Unless it is cancer.
我就不负责了
Then I'm out.
麦克斯  这是七号桌的账单
And, Max, here is check for table seven.
姐牛吧
Booyah!
看个医生是得等多久啊
How long is it gonna take to see a doctor?
我绝对是生什么病了  现在是病发前期
I'm definitely getting something-- I'm pre-sick.
我现在是初期的病发前期
I'm stage one pre-sick.
我需要青霉素
I need penicillin.
我跟你说过了  你得硬起
I told you before, you have to man up
坚决跟病魔抗争到底
and not give in to this sick stuff.
我又不像你
I'm not like you.
我是个有感觉的人
I have actual things I feel.
米那肯·古德曼
Menachem Goldman.
这一带肯定是正统的犹太社区
This must be the orthodox Jewish neighborhood.
不然就是ZZ托普村了
Either that or we're in ZZ Top-ville.
麦克斯  放尊重点
Max, have some respect.
我超级敬重的好不好
Hey, I got nothing but respect.
他们可是发明南方摇滚的乐团呢
They basically invented southern rock.
我超喜欢犹太人
I love the Jewish people.
以前一觉得自己病了
Whenever I felt sick before,
我就跑到隔壁别墅  找克莱医生
I'd just pop over to the townhouse next door and visit Dr. Klein.
所以谁有药丸你就爱谁啊
So your love was contingent on pills?
咱俩根本是一丘之貉嘛
We're not that different.
其实以前我跟克莱一家关系很好
Actually, the Kleins and I were very close.
我多次被邀请去他们家过逾越节呢
I was invited to many passover in their home.
他们以前还称我为"荣誉犹太人"呢
In fact, they called me their honorary Jew.
里芙卡·尚舍罗威茨
Rivka Shemshelewitz.
人家的犹太名比你帅气多了
Well, you're no Rivka Shemshelewitz.
克莱夫人总说我有"细尘"犹太血统呢
Mrs. Klein always said I had a bissel Jew.
你还有台犹太的"吸尘"器啊
You had a Jewish vacuum cleaner?
不  是"细尘"啦
No. Bissel.
是意第绪语中  少量的意思
It's a Yiddish word. It means little.
有一次我得了细尘感冒
And this one time I had a bissel flu
她就天天送鸡汤给我喝
and she brought me chicken soup every day.
那你直接打给克莱医生不得了
So why don't you just give Dr. Klein a call?
我打了三次都没人回
I did three times and no return.
他估计不想跟我沾上边了吧
I guess he doesn't want anything to do with me anymore
我爸弄了这么大的财务丑闻
because of my father's financial scandal.
那么多年来  我以为我们亲如家人
All those years I thought we were family.
原来只是我自作多情
Guess not.
不一定吧  有求必不应
I don't know, ignoring your needs
视你如空气
and pretending you don't exist?
我觉得这就是家人啊
Sounds like family to me.
卡洛琳·钱宁  卡洛琳·钱宁
Caroline Channing, Caroline Channing.
终于啊
Finally.
我来跟她说吧
Let me do the talking.
我以前跟克莱夫人学了不少希伯来语呢
I learned a lot of Hebrew from Mrs. Klein.
我跟他们是一国的
These are my people.
您好  平安  新年快乐[希伯来语]
Hello, shalom, shana tova
很好  要再多抖几个词直到太阳下山吗
Very good, you wanna squeeze in a couple more before sundown?
你就跟我想装爱尔兰人
Wow, you're as bad as me trying to be Irish
跟人家骗啤酒一样逊
at the blarney rose for a free beer.
喂  能给我来杯啤酒吗[爱尔兰口音]
Yar, can I get me a cerveza?
两位有什么需要吗
What can I get you ladies,
除了更端庄的裙子之外的
besides skirts that are more appropriate?
抱歉  我们不知道这里是正统的犹太区
Sorry, I didn't know it was an orthodox neighborhood.
这样吧  我们把外套绑腰上挡着吧
You know what, we could just tie our coats around our waists.
麦克斯
Max?
哎哟  看看这妞的大胸
Oh, and look at the breasts on this one.
穿还是脱  赶快决定
Coat on or off? Make up your mind.
宝贝  我只是说
No, Bubala, I'm just saying,
这对大胸  加上这头秀发
with those big breasts and that gorgeous hair,
我们简直是一个模子刻出来的
it's like looking in a mirror.
虽然老娘青春不在  但相信我
It's been a few years, but trust me,
脱下假发和白大褂  咱俩一模一样啊
under this wig and smock, spitting image of you.
给  艾丝特·瑞荷
Here you go, Esther Rachael.
不然你觉得我是怎么嫁得
How else do you think I landed
我老公安舍尔这样的英俊医生呢
a handsome doctor like my Anshell?
抱歉  医生
Oh, doctor?
医生  医生  你可以...
Doctor? Doctor, if you could--
靠  希伯来语的"稍等"怎么说来着
oh, oh, what is that Hebrew word for wait?
你还是老老实实说英语吧
You might wanna start peppering in some English.
小妞  你现在才说
Now, Chava?
你现在才说你病重不能给我烤蛋糕了
Now you're telling me you're too sick to bake.
我需要80个小蛋糕呢
I need 80 cupcakes.
成人礼是明天呢
The Bar Mitzvah is tomorrow.
给老娘死一边去
You're dead to me!
下周见吧
See you next week.
-我们能帮你  -我们能吗
- We could help. - We can?
可以啊  名片给我
Yeah, give me the card.
你好  我是麦克斯
Hi, I'm Max
我们有个小蛋糕生意
and my friend and I here have a cupcake business
我们很乐意帮你做成人礼的小蛋糕
and we'd be happy to bake as many cupcakes
要多少都没问题
as you need for the bar mitzvah.
你需要小蛋糕  我们会做小蛋糕
I mean, you need cake, we make cake.
真是"命中注定"啊[意第绪语]
It's bashert.
够了  少来那套"有缘千里犹太牵"了
Look, enough with the "it's a small Hebrew world after all."
收费250块如何
How does 250 sound?
不行  要275块
No way, 275.
我得忙活一早上呢
I have to bake all morning.
连性格都一模一样
It's like looking in a mirror.
是犹太洁食吧
They're kosher, right?
是不是犹太洁食  你看我
Are they kosher? Look at me.
咱俩还需要多说吗
Like looking in a mirror.
很好  我会打电话告诉你们地址的
Good, I'll call you with the address.
艾丝特·瑞荷  我能跟你丈夫谈
Esther Rachael, if I could talk to you husband
买些抗生素的...
about getting some antibiotics--
抱歉  日落了
Sorry, sundown.
我买了犹太洁食食谱
Okay, I've got the kosher cookbook,
盐  面粉  糖  新的搅拌碗
salt, flour, sugar, new mixing bowls,
还去了趟善心二手店
and I stopped at the goodwill
买了两件明天穿的端庄素色衣服
and got us two appropriately sad schmatas to wear for tomorrow.
开工吧
Let's start.
什么开工  我都做一半了
Start? I'm already half done.
你怎么可能做完一半了
How could you be half done?
你又没有洁食用的材料
You didn't have any kosher ingredients.
他们又吃不出来
Oh, they'll never know,
我们说是洁食的就行了
we'll just tell them they're kosher.
天啊  不可以这样
Oh, my God, we can't do that.
天啊  已经这样了
Oh, my God, we just did.
必须做成洁食才行
They have to be kosher.
你就不怕遭天谴吗
Do you want God to smite us?
老天还能怎么惩罚我们
What's he gonna do?
收回我的好运和你的亿万家财吗
Take away all my good luck and your fortune?
难道写着低脂的食物真是低脂的吗
You think all those things labeled low fat are low fat?
不过是销售把戏罢了
It is just a sales gimmick.
有次我吃了根低卡冰棒
I had a low cal ice cream bar once
我牛仔裤的扣子立马就给崩了
that popped my top Jean button.
犹太洁食不是销售把戏
Kosher isn't a sales gimmick.
是人家千年来的传统
It's thousands of years of tradition.
我们得尊重人家啊
We have to respect that.
我从不尊重任何人的传统
I don't respect anyone's tradition.
这就是我的传统
That's kind of my tradition.
也许是因为
Well maybe that's because
你成长过程中没有家人陪在身边吧
you didn't grow up around a family.
我成长过程中有无数家人好吗
Hey, I grew up with a lot of families.
曼森家  杰克森家  米南德兹家
The Manson family, the Jackson family, the Menendezes.
等等  是念米南德兹还是米南戴兹
Wait, is that Menendezes or Menen-di?
反正他们都待我如兄长
Either way, they were like brothers to me.
麦克斯  我们就老老实实做洁食吧
Max, we are doing these straight up kosher.
好吧
Fine.
你把新搅拌碗拿去退了吧  不需要
But return those new bowls, I don't need them.
我把培根都捞出来就能接着用了
I can just dump the bacon bits out of this old one.
麦克斯  你就得重新做吧
Max, please, let's just start the cupcakes over,
明天交货  收钱  买抗生素
drop them off, get me some antibiotics,
然后回家  让我上床养病
come home, and put me to bed.
行行行  我做成洁食就是了
All right, I'll make them kosher.
这也是你欠人家的  谁让你骗了人家
I mean, it's the least you could do after you lied to that woman
还让她误以为你是犹太人
and let her think you were one of them.
我又不知道我爹是谁
Hey, I don't know who my father is.
我很可能有一半犹太血统啊
I could be half Jewish.
不过我更可能是酒保的女儿
Although it's more likely I'm half bartender
可能当年我妈被拐着"酒债肉偿"
who demanded my mom figure out a way to pay her tab.
-你们好啊  -你好啊
- Hey! - Hello.
小瑟格正准备回我家
Serguisz and I are on way up to my apartment.
他要做早午餐给我吃
He's making me brunch.
童子鸡撒上我的独家酱料
Cornish hens splashed with my special sauce.
我好爱独家酱料啊  爱死了
I love special sauce, I love that!
我来主要是想问你们
Yeah, and I stopped by because I was hoping you girls
有没有多余的小蛋糕给我们当点心
might have some spare cupcakes for dessert.
大概有40个吧
Only about 40 of them.
太好了
Oh, good!
我先上楼开煮吧
I'll go up and get started.
苏菲  钥匙能给我吗
Sophie, can I have you keys?
-没问题  -你家真有爱
- Oh, yeah. - Cute place.
哎呀  我也有一样的钥匙圈呢
Ah, I have keychain just like this.
我们真是心有灵犀啊
We are birds of a feather.
爱死了
I love that!
小妞们  看见没
See, girls.
我就爱我新男人这一点
This is what I like about my new boyfriend.
他对什么东西都有爱
He loves so many things.
唯独对阴道无爱
And vagina ain't one of them.
麦克斯
Max!
我们又不了解人家
We don't know that.
这年头  性向本来就很随意
Sexuality is more fluid these days.
没事的  他就是个基爆的基佬
It's okay. He's big, big gay.
你知道他是基啊
So... You know he's gay?
何止是知道
Oh, know it?
我特意找的
I prefer it.
我前夫是个粗鲁的恶汉
Yeah, my ex-husband was large male bully.
房事粗暴  满裆精斑
Yeah, all rough sex and stains in shorts.
我想要个只抱抱  不搞搞的男人
Now all I want is a man who will spoon me and stay soft.
那性生活怎么办
But what about sex?
男根虽好  我手更巧
Oh, no one does me better than me.
这里是最后一批了
That's the last of them.
瞧咱们这身
Look at us.
我觉得看起来挺不错的
I think we look very nice.
是吗
Really?
我觉得看起来像奥尔森姐妹
I think we look like the Olson twins.
你们好啊  女孩们
Well hello, girls.
你们看起来真美
You look very lovely.
恭喜你们家[意第绪语]
Mazel tov to the family.
能来参与  我们深感荣幸[意第绪语]
What a mitzvah to be part of this day.
命运的巧合啊[意第绪语]
How bashert.
你还没抖够意第绪语吗
Oh, we're still on that ride?
真是抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是很开心能来
It's just, I'm so happy to be
你温暖有爱的家
in your warm and wonderful home.
我以前跟我的邻居克莱一家很熟
I was very close to my neighbors, the Kleins.
他们还称我为荣誉犹太人呢
In fact, they called me their honorary Jew.
别说了
Stop now.
这就你对厄尔套近乎
This is like when you tell Earl
说自己是黑人一样窘
you're practically black.
我们收完钱就走
We'll just get our money and go.
收完钱就走
Take our money and go?
我们又不是无礼的野蛮人
What are we, barbarians?
留下来一起庆祝吧
Stay and celebrate a little.
不过只许待在厨房  不准靠近男人
But, out here in the kitchen, away from the men.
坐下  快吃  来嘛[高潮]
Sit, eat, come.
我人生最爱的三件事
Three of my favorite things to do.
又美又幽默  不娶太可惜啊
Good looks and funny. What a catch.
哈达莎  拿个勺子过来
Hadassa, hand me a spoon.
百分百洁食  好吃到你昏倒
All 100% kosher and so gorgeous you could plotz.
她看太多芭芭拉·史翠珊的电影了吧
This one's seen some Streisand movies, yes?
等吃过我的面再下定论吧
Wait until you taste my kugel.
我超爱犹太面
Oh, I love kugel.
告诉我  艾丝特·瑞荷
Tell me, Esther Rachael,
你是阿什肯纳兹犹太人  还是塞法迪犹太人
are you Ashkenazi or Sephardic Jews?
有人专门上网做足功课哦
Someone's been on the Internet.
我靠  这是意大利面加甜点啊
No way, this is a pasta and a dessert?
他来啦
Ooh, there he is.
我的独子  我的小天使
My only son. My little angel.
今天成年礼的主角  从男孩变男人
The Bar Mitzvah boy who, today, becomes a man.
姑娘们  这是史姆里
Girls, this is Shmuley
跟他的邻居朋友大卫
and his friend from next door, David.
孩子们  跟做小蛋糕的姑娘们问个好吧
Say hello to the girls who made the cupcakes, boys.
很高兴见到你们
Nice to meet you.
哈达莎  达沃拉  够了
Hadassa, Devorah, enough.
谢谢你们  走吧
Thank you, go.
享受派对吧
Enjoy the party.
多吃点面
Have more kugel.
我去跟我丈夫要你们的钱
I'll go ask my husband for your money.
麦克斯  我就喜欢这些
See, this is what I love, Max.
家庭  传统
The family, the tradition.
意大利面加超多葡萄干
The lasagna with the crazy raisins.
还有那两个男孩
And those two little boys,
他们还能再可爱一点吗
could they have been more precious?
哟哟哟  干毛呢  小蛋糕骚妞们
Yo, yo, yo, what up cupcake bitches?
小爷我也要搞个像她们这样
I'm fixin' to marry me a biatch
会烤会搞的淫娃当老婆
who bakes like this, son.
我不知道你们怎么了
Uh, I don't know what's going on,
但是依照你们的传统
but I'm pretty sure boys and girls
男女是不应该交谈的  对吗
aren't supposed to be socializing, right?
哇靠  小美女  虽然你能说善道
Damn, sweetness, your lips are moving
但小王想的都是你的小翘臀啊
but your ass is doing all the talking.
他是在说意第绪语吗
Uh... Is that Yiddish?
你们俩在这啊  快过来
Oh, boys, there you are, come on.
跟小蛋糕女士们说再见
Say goodbye to the cupcake ladies.
很高兴见到你们
Nice to meet you.
是真有其事  还是我发烧到出现幻觉了
Did that just happen or has my fever suddenly spiked?
我这辈子第一次见到
That's the first time I ever saw anyone
脸上还在长痘的痞子
acting all pimp who still had pimples.
哟哟哟
Yo, yo, yo!
小痞子二度回归
And they're back.
怎么样啊  小骚货们
What up, Shawties?
在搞毛呢
What's crackalackin?
今天我兄弟要成人啦
Yo, today my boy became a mans.
没错
That's right.
赶紧来"搞"个"成年"仪式吧
Got my bar mitzvah done, son.
没错
Preach!
赶紧开始吧
So let's get to it.
要给多少"成年金"
How much of my Mitzvah money
你才愿意脱掉上衣
is it gonna take for you to pop that top
让小王尝尝你的顶级人间"胸"器啊
and serve me up some super fine taytays?
拜托  就算你给再多钱也...
Dude, there is not enough money in the--
最多能给多少来着
how much are we talking?
麦克斯
Max!
别嫉妒她  小白妞
Yo, don't get all jealous, vanilla cone.
转身把屁股翘起来  给小爷乐呵乐呵吧
How about you turn around and make it pop for daddy?
你妈可就在隔壁哦
How would you like it if I told your mother
如果我告诉她你们多轻浮
right on the other side of that door
对我们有多不敬  会怎么样
how you boys were in here disrespecting us?
朕会用龙根堵住你这贱婢的嘴
How is you gonna say anything with your mouth full?
绝啊  兄弟
Damn, son!
妈  快过来  这边
Come in here, ma. This way.
千万别告诉她
Don't say anything to her.
我们拿完钱就走
Let's just get our money and get out of here.
麦克斯  她该知道的
Max, she should know.
你想毁了人家的成年礼外加收不到钱吗
You wanna ruin their day and not get paid?
再多忍五分钟  我们就能走人了
Just keep it to yourself for five minutes and we're gone.
我想你们见见我母亲  辛妲·菲格
I want you to meet my mother, Hinda Fagel.
妈  洁食小蛋糕就是这位麦克斯做的
Ma, this is Max who made the kosher cupcakes.
我是卡洛琳
And I'm Caroline.
那女娃说什么呢
What did the shicksa say?
她说她叫卡洛琳
She said her name is Caroline.
谁管她叫什么呢
Who cares what her name is?
她长得就跟当年
She looks like the people that
偷我奶奶储物箱的人一样
stole my grandmother's good hutch.
这个女娃就不一样了
But look at this one.
长得跟我一样美
It's like looking in a mirror.
哎呀  她发烧呢
Oy, she's got a fever.
麦克斯  宝贝  你在发烧呢
Oh, Max, oh honey, you're burning up.
不可能  我从来不生病
Oh, no way, I don't get sick.
我会生病哦
I get sick.
你生病了
You're sick.
跟我过来  好好躺着休息
You'll come, you'll lie down.
我真的没事
Oh, I'm really fine.
我们收了钱就回家了
We'll just get our money and head home.
胡说  留下来让我老公看看
Nonsense. You'll see my husband.
医生老公哦
The doctor.
等等  你们带她去哪里呢
Stop, wait, where are you taking her?
我才是会生病的那个呀
I'm the one who gets sick.
她说啥呢
What did she say?
她说她也要偷你的储物箱
She says she wants your hutch.
你个可怜的娃
You poor baby.
你都烧到38.9度了
You have a fever of 102.
乖乖休息吧  亲爱的
Just have to rest, Bubala.
我真的没事
I'm really fine.
这毛巾也太舒服了吧
That towel thing feels awesome.
这是冰枕  让你赶紧退烧
It's a cold compress, it'll bring your fever down.
我老公马上就来了
My husband should be in any minute.
谢谢
Thanks.
我应该老实告诉你
I think it's only right to tell you,
我不太了解我的真实身世
I don't know a lot about my background, so...
我可能不是犹太人哦
I might not be Jewish.
傻孩子  瞧你的长相
Please, look at you.
如果我有女儿  肯定长你这样
You could be my daughter.
那样该多好啊
I would have liked that.
我一直希望有个女儿
Always wanted a daughter.
我也一直希望有个妈妈
I always wanted a mother.
你母亲早逝吗
Oh, did your mother die young?
很遗憾  仍在世
Sadly, no.
让我给你一个吻
Ooh, you need a kiss.
太好了  你的汤来了
Oh, good your soup is ready.
喝"细尘"[点]吧  亲爱的
Ess a bissel, tatelleh.
细尘
Bissel?
我懂"细尘"这词
I know bissel.
你当然懂  你是犹太人嘛
Of course you do. You're Jewish.
是就是吧  其他都见鬼去
Okay, I'm Jewish, what the hell.
我们不相信有地狱
Oh, we don't believe in hell.
不信吗
We don't?
太爽了
Awesome.
谢谢您
Oh, thanks.
叫我嬷嬷[意第绪语]
Call me bubby.
谢谢  嬷嬷
Thanks, bubby.
从来没人帮我吹过汤
No one's ever blown on my soup before.
那些人脑子有病吗
What's wrong with them?
瞧我兄弟  瞧我兄弟
That's my boy, that's my boy, hey,
厉害啊
Hey, ho. Oh, there he go!
小爷就是这么牛逼  淫娃
That's what's up, hooker.
首先
First of all,
你刚把他妈妈刚打蜡的地板给磨掉了
you just scuffed his mother's freshly-waxed floor
其次
and secondly,
你现在可能觉得无视家族传统很酷
you may think throwing away your family traditions is cool now,
但若干年后  报应会来的
but in life, bad things can happen.
某天  当你发现自己身无分文  疾病缠身时
And one day, when you find yourself penniless and sick,
你会想念你善良的犹太家人
you'll need your nice Jewish family
然而你电话打再多  他们也不会理你
and you'll call them three times and they won't answer the phone
才不管你病得多重多需要抗生素
no matter how much you need antibiotics.
宝贝啊
Damn, boo,
你说到"刚除毛的..."小王就没在听了
I stopped listening after you said freshly-waxed.
妙啊
Playa!
麦克斯  我开了些阿莫西林
Max, I'm giving you some amoxicillin
让你带回家吃
for you to take home.
乖乖把药都吃完
Now take it all,
好转了也得持续吃
even when you start feeling better.
是的  安舍尔医生
Yes, Dr. Anshell.
看我拿什么来了
Look what I brought.
给甜心们的甜点
Sweets for the sweets.
稍等一下  吃之前我有话要说
Uh, wait, wait, wait, before you eat those,
我不是说我可能不是犹太人吗
remember how I said I might not be Jewish?
-是啊  -它们也可能不是洁食
- Yes. - Those might not be kosher.
你说什么呢
What are you saying?
那些不是洁食
I'm saying they're not kosher.
她说啥呢
What is she saying?
不是洁食
Not kosher!
-什么  -不是洁食
- What? - Not kosher!
妈  快吐出来
Spit it out, ma!
快吐出来
Spit it out!
再等一下  这太好吃了
Just a minute, it tastes so good.
-爽吗  -停下
- You like that? - Stop.
-爽不爽  -别撒了
- You like that? - Stop it.
-爽死了吧  -停...  够了
- You like that? - S--that's it!
听好  再把毛爷爷往老娘身上撒
Listen, hit me with one more dead president
老娘就把你们拖出去  跟其他死饶舌歌手埋一起
and you'll be six feet under with Biggie and Tupac.
听懂老娘的话没  假饶舌娃子
You understand me, Jew-Tang Clan?
排骨淫娃想开战啦
Skinny bitch came to play!
什么样的人会做非洁食小蛋糕
What kind of girl brings non-kosher cupcakes
给洁食家庭啊
into a kosher home?
不是我  我不是那样的人
Not me-- I'm not that kind of girl.
是我  我就是那样的人
Yeah, hi, I think I'm that kind of girl.
麦克斯  你说什么呢
Max, what are you talking about?
我确保了每一个小蛋糕
I made sure every single one of those
都达到了超严厉的洁食标准
was up to a rabbi's high standard.
我的"超严厉"标准不够高  行了吧
Yes, well, maybe my rabbi didn't have such high standards.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry,
我不小心烤糊了几个  时间又不够
I burned some and we were running late
我就想  80个中混4个进去
and I figured, four non-kosher out of 80.
不多嘛
So close.
麦克斯  我跟你说过洁食传统
Max, I told you how important
对这些犹太家庭有多重要
all those traditions are to a Jewish family.
是啊  你跟我说过传统跟家庭
Yes, you told me about tradition and family,
但在冰枕敷到我头上前
but none of that meant anything
那些对我毫无意义
until I felt that cold compress.
而且她还善良到亲手帮我敷上
And she was nice enough to put it on my head
我这才明白传统跟家庭的含义
and I felt what that feels like.
然后嬷嬷在吃非洁食小蛋糕前
And then bubby blew on my soup
还帮我把汤吹凉了
before she ate the non-kosher cupcake.
什么  嬷嬷还吃了非洁食小蛋糕
Wait, bubby ate a non-kosher cupcake?
家门不幸啊
It's a shanda!
的确是家门不幸
It is a shanda.
我希望这词是指
I'm hoping shanda means
你会原谅我  然后付我钱吗
you're forgiven and we'll pay you anyway.
我们不会收任何费用
We are not taking any money.
那当然  你们半毛钱都别想拿
That's right, you're not taking anything.
但把这个冰枕拿走吧
Except for this compress.
早日康复
Feel better.
可以滚了  有多远滚多远
Now go, get out of my sight.
还有  别再穿短裙了
And don't wear short skirts.
艾丝特·瑞荷
Esther Rachel,
我想跟你谈谈你儿子
I wanna talk to you about your son
史姆里今天的一些事
Shmuley's behavior today.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我的小史姆里干了什么好事
What did my Shmuley do?
我告诉你吧
I'll tell you what he did.
他今天长大成人了
He became a man.
没其他的了
That's all he did.
对吧  卡洛琳
Right, Caroline?
的确是"成人"了啊
I'll say he became a man.
你什么意思呢
What are you talking about?
史姆里
Shmuley!
别多管闲事了
Stay out of it,
这又不是我们的家
this is not our family.
你跟我都是没家的人了
You and I don't have a family.
人家还有呢
They still do.
以后会有警察去跟她说的
Let the police tell her about him.
我儿子怎么啦
So about my Shmuley.
你刚想说什么呢
What do you have to say?
恭喜恭喜  他是个很好的少年
Mazel tov, he's a wonderful, wonderful boy.
你们来啦
Oh, there you are.
史姆里  大卫  跟小蛋糕姑娘们说再见
Shmuley, David, say goodbye to the cupcake girls.
很高兴见到你们
Nice to meet you.
谢谢
Thank you.
麦克斯没来啊
So I see no Max.
她还病着呢
She still out sick?
她今晚刚回来上班
It's her first night back.
她马上就会到了
She should be here any minute.
你想点餐吗
Did you wanna order something
还是等你男人呢
or wait for your boyfriend?
我跟他悲剧收场了
Oh, see, this is sad story.
他跟我分手  找别的"女人"去了
Uh, he broke off with me to date other woman.
那女人有鸡鸡呢
And she had penis.
我哪赢得过"带把"的女人啊
Yeah, I can't compete with that.
你好吗  厄尔
Hi, Earl.
我失散已久的爱终于回来了
There she is, my long lost love.
你身子怎么样了  麦克斯
How you feeling, Max?
病好得差不多了
I'm pretty good.
你好啊  嬷嬷
Hey, bubby.
我给你带了些鸡汤
I brought you some chicken soup
感谢你近几日的照顾
for taking care of me the last couple days.
我很喜欢当你"嬷嬷"的感觉
I enjoyed being your bubby.
我想你错了  麦克斯
I guess you were wrong, Max.
你和我还有家  我们就是彼此的家人
You and I do have family--each other.
没上过法院  互相指控对方是杀人凶手前
We're not family until we have to testify against each other
我们当不了真正的家人
in a manslaughter trial.
来  吃吧
Here, eat this.
我不想你染上我的病
I don't want you to catch what I just had.
不可能的  麦克斯
Not gonna happen, Max.
我听了你的话
I took your advice.
硬起
I manned up.
跟病魔单挑
I stared germs in the face.
没错  你生病  我生猛
That's right, when you got sick, I got balls.
姐牛吧
Booyah!
简直跟我一模一样
Like looking in a mirror.